#### RTOGARCÍA M B Е

CÉSAR HUMBERTO GRIFALDO GARCÍA

# - IT ENGINEER 🗕

## **OBJECTIVE**

I am a solution-focused developer with experience in web-based applications. Participated in the development and deployment of IT products. Supported companies' business objectives and strategies while gaining real-world experience. Passionate in working with multi-disciplinary teams, always open to learn new technologies which can help the company's objectives. Accustomed to working in agile environments.

## **EDUCATION**

# Information Technology (IT) Engineering

Universidad Politécnica de Tlaxcala, Sept 2019 - Dec 2022:

- Awarded with "Mejores Mil de Tlaxcala" and Excellence scholarships.
- Participated with team in development of two systems for college utilizing PHP Framework.

## **Mechatronics Engineering**

Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla, Sept 2016 - Jun 2019

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Apple Fullstack Career**

Platzi, Aug 2022 - Nov 2022:

 Built a Twitter clone to get to the conclusion of my iOS Platzi journey implementing everything I had learnt, e.g., construction of UI utilizing AutoLayout and CocoaTouch classes according to the given design, implementation of Firebase to canalize the storage of user's images and videos, consummation of RESTful API to get the tweets information from the server as well as storing them, construction of the app according to the MVC architecture, integration of third-party libraries to add different functionalities using Cocoapods, and managing iPhone hardware to get access to the camera and user location.

## iOS Development Bootcamp

Udemy, Jun 2022 - Sept 2022:

- Learnt the full iOS development process to create iOS applications from zero to hero.
- Built different applications to understand specific topics like seques, persistence, API consummation, etc.
- Joint different communities with the main purpose to learn iOS development and make networking.

### Student Practices Experience:

- Web Developer Intern, Grupo ABX: April 2022 June 2022
- Software Engineer Practitioner, Deloitte: Nov 2021 Jan 2022
- Front End Practitioner, Creative Technology Center La Colmena: Aug 2021 Jan 2022
- Database Intern, ALBA DTI: Sept 2020 Jan 2021

# **SOFT & HARD SKILLS**

Soft: Collaborative, Communicative, Analytical, Team Player, Supportive, Resilient, Empathic, Leadership, Flexible, Objective oriented, Adaptable, Motivational, Self-Taught, Inclusive

Hard: Swift, UlKit, Cocoa Touch, Object Oriented Programming, Protocol Oriented Programming, SwiftUI, CocoaPods, Core Data, UserDefaults, URLSession, Alamofire, RESTful APIs, MVC, MVVM, VIPER, SQL, NoSQL, Firebase, Unit Testing, Scrum, Objective-C, Git, Github, Postman

Languages: Technical Conversational Advanced English (C1), Native Spanish Speaker, Basic German (A2)

## CERTIFICATIONS

- Apple Full Stack: Platzi
- iOS & Swift: The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp: Udemy



Tlaxcala, México

bertochgg@gmail.com







